Finding Aid for B. E. Allen Papers, 1950-1971
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
B. E. Allen papers 1950-1971
Allen, B. E. (Basil Ernest), 1919-
2.5 linear ft.
85587 Aa 2
Manager of Woodlands Division of Union Bag-Camp Corporation, Savannah, Georgia, manufacturers of paper, bags, and boxes, and vice president and council member of Society of American Foresters. Correspondence and other materials concerning forest land use and Allen's activities with Society of American Foresters.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of B. E. Allen (donor no. 5023 ) and came to the library in 1971.
The collection is open to research.
B. E. Allen was manager of the Woodlands Division of the Union Bag-Camp Corp. in Savannah, Georgia. He was also active in his professional organization, the Society of American Foresters serving as vice-president and council member.
The collection consists of correspondence and other materials relating to forest land use and his activities with the Society of American Foresters.
Subjects:
Conservation of natural resources--United States.; Forests and forestry--United States.; Natural resources.; Society of American Foresters.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; Allen, B. E. (Basil Ernest), 1919-
- Correspondence and other papers
  - 1950-February 1963, 31 folders (Box 1)
  - March 1963-1971, 20 folders (Box 2)
- Society of American Foresters
  - Membership committee, 1959-1966, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Legislative committee, 1962-1964 (Box 2)
  - Membership grades, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Planning committee, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Study of the small forest land ownership situation, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Allen's campaigns for president of the Society of American Foresters, 1961-1964 (Box 3)
  - Division of Forest Engineering, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Papers,1970 1971concerning the Committee on Forest Land Use, 1970-1971, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Printed material and reports, 1960-1965, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Miscellanea, 1956-1968 (Box 3)